Senaike Michael Oluwatobi Lagos, Nigeria

senaikepooldis@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/senaike-michael oluwatobi-96053b19b

## **Summary**

I am an Innovative Software Engineer, Frontend Web, Backend Web Engineer, Web Designer, Broadcast Producer, Blogger and Creative writer, with a wealth of experience within the IT/programming world and all aspects of broadcast production.

Apart from my above stated abilities, I am also a visionary creator, researcher, content developer, creative writer, storyteller and documentary and feature film maker, with demonstrated ability to take an idea from concept to delivery.

Furthermore, I also possess a collaborative attribute in retrospect to working closely with strategic and creative teams to develop not only software and IT related endeavours but also produce quality broadcast and creative contents, which are deemed fit for public consumption.

Though, barely 2 years into Tech/web development, I have been able to surmount some of my expectations and limits, as demonstrated recently by my inclusion into the list of 250 finalists, out of over 14 thousand Software developers, Mobile Application Developers, UI/UX Designers, DevOps, Frontend Developers and, Backend Web Engineers across the globe, at the HNGi8 Internship.

# **Experience**

Zari.

# Software and Full-Stack Web Engineer

Zuri Team, Inc.

June 2022 - Sept 2022 (5 months)

Already familiar with the concept of backend web development as a previous intern in the program, this time, I was introduced to full-stack web development, using the Python and JavaScript programming languages respectively, as well as some of its tools and frameworks.

## **Website Designer**

Freelance

Jan 2022 - Present (2 months +)

Learned the fundamentals and basics of web designing using the WordPress CMS technology.

# **Software & Backend Web Engineer**

Zuri Chat

Oct 2021 - Present (5 months +)

#### **Television Producer**

Superscreen Television

Jan 2020 - Present (2 years 2 months +)

Presented production ideas and determined creative scenarios for production and delivery.

Realigned production schedules to factor in changing conditions such as materials shortages and changing designs.

Coordinated production schedules and activities for 3 shows for Superscreen television network.

# Senaike Michael Oluwatobi - page 1

Coordinated with producers and on-air talent to create program content, new ideas and segments.

Conceptualized, researched, developed and pitched stories that reflected unique sensibilities of the TV station.

#### Co Producer

National Broadcast Academy

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020 (3 months)

As a co-producer, i was part of the production team that worked on a radio magazine programme, to mark the 2020 World Radio Day in Nigeria, on behalf of the National Broadcast Academy.

· market

# **Backend Web Engineer**

**HNG** Internship

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021 (3 months)

As a software engineer intern in HNG - which is regarded as one of toughest tech internships in Nigeria we were tasked with building a remote work platform -first of its kind- synonymous to Slack and Discord, using very innovative tools, languages, and frameworks.

Furthermore, I was also selected as one of the 250 finalists out of 14 thousand software developers, designers, mobile app developers and, devops.

Zari

## Software and Backend Web Engineer

Zuri Team, Inc.

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021 (5 months)

As a software engineer intern, I was introduced to the art of programming through the Python programming language, as well as some of its tools and frameworks.

I was also able to deliver on time, tasks and projects necessary for my self-assessment and improvement using the Django framework.

Also, I was able to work with a team of designers, frontend developers, backend developers and mobile app developers to conceptualize and create an E-Commerce app known as "Ayalo", which replicated some of the features and functions of Airbnb.

Zaris

# Software and Full-Stack Web Engineer

Zuri Team, Inc.

June 2022 - Sept 2022 (3 months)

As a Fullstack web developer intern, I was introduced to full-stack web development, using the Python and JavaScript programming languages respectively, as well as some of its tools and frameworks.

#### **Executive Producer**

Federal Radio Corporation of Nigeria/National Broadcast

Academy Mar 2020 - Mar 2020 (1 month)

As a production student, I conceptualized, researched and, with a well-defined interview, i produced a radio documentary titled "Journey Through Time; A Tale of Seven Thrones". The documentary was centred on a brief narrative of the seven grandchildren of Oduduwa-the progenitor of the Yoruba race-, who set off from Ile-Ife to forge new kingdoms of their

Senaike Michael Oluwatobi - page 2 own.

#### Co Producer

National Broadcast Academy Feb 2020 - Feb 2020 (1 month)

As a production student at the National Broadcast Academy, i and a crew of four other producers worked on a radio drama on open defecation. This was to enable a behavioural change within the minds of the listener as to the ills of open defecation and its consequences such as malaria.

#### **Radio Producer**

RN1 FM 103.5 (Radio Nigeria)

2020 - 2020 (1 year)

Conducted research, gathered information from multiple sources and presented results.

As a production intern, i was tutored on various forms of production, primarily on documentaries and feature film production

#### **Editor In Chief**

Nubia Republic

2015 - 2020 (6 years)

As the Editor-in-chief and publisher of Nubia Republic, which was a blog, I extensively researched and published articles from various fields such as; History, ancient civilizations, conspiracy theories, military formations, politics, nature and entertainment.

Established editorial direction and publication policies and procedures and monitored and maintained functional consistency.



#### ICT Member

National Youth Service Corps

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 (11 months)

As an ICT CDS member, we brainstormed, taught and learned various technologies and frameworks needed not only as individuals, but as an alternative cure to the menace of job insecurity within the country.



#### **Teacher**

National Youth Service Corps

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 (11 months)

During my period as a Teacher/Corper, I taught various subjects such as English Language, Literature in-English, Government and, Civic Education, to students within the classes of SSS1-SSS3.

#### **Political Writer and Editor**

Insider Newspaper 2016 - 2017 (2 years)

### Senaike Michael Oluwatobi - page 3

As a student political writer and editor at the Insider Newspaper, Obafemi Awolowo University, i researched and wrote extensively within my area of specialization, which was primarily on politics and men in power, both within and outside the shores of the country.

#### **Education**



# Dbafemi Awolowo University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, English Language and Literature 2013 - 2017

# **National Broadcast Academy**

Production, Production 2020 - 2020

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

**Production** - National Broadcast Academy

# English For Specific Purposes - Obafemi Awolowo University

#### Skills

Creative Writing Software Development **Broadcast**  Production • Writing • Content Development • Film Production • Penetration Testing • Programming • Blogger • Adobe Premiere Pro

#### **Honours & Awards**

Finalist - HNG

Oct 2021

I was selected as one of the 250 finalists out of over 14 thousand IT practitioners from various fields.

### **PORFOLIO LINK**

The link below contains some of my hosted sites and apps.

https://senaikemichael.netlify.app/

Senaike Michael Oluwatobi - page 4